Finding Aid for Florence Ernestine Schleicher Teed papers, ca. 1860-ca. 1890 and 1919-1953
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Florence Ernestine Schleicher Teed papers circa 1860-1890 and 1919-1953
Teed, Florence Ernestine Schleicher, 1901-1954.
2.3 linear feet
86103 Aa 2
Graduate of University of Michigan and ordained Methodist minister. Correspondence; Sermons and other inspirational writings; Course materials, Published materials; and Photographs.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Wallace Teed (donor no. 1046 ).
Periodic additions to the records are not expected.
The collection is open to research.
Florence Ernestine Schleicher Teed was born on Sept. 1, 1901, in Ann Arbor, a daughter of Frederick and Eleanor Krantz Schleicher. She attended Barnard College in New York and graduated from the University of Michigan Literary College in 1926. In 1927, she received the degree of Bachelor of Evangelistic Theology from the Chicago Evangelistic Institute and soon thereafter was ordained at the Detroit Conference of the Methodist Episcopal Church.
In 1928, Schleicher married R. Wallace Teed. Since her ordination, she had been active in evangelistic work, speaking before women's groups, writing a book and articles for monthly magazines. Beginning in 1953, she conducted a Sunday radio series "Faith for Living," over radio station WPAG.
Mrs. Teed was a member of the First Methodist Church and organizer of the Women's Society for Christian Service at the church. She was an organizer of the Washtenaw County Medical Society Auxiliary and the Washtenaw County Infirmary Auxiliary. She was on the Salvation Army board of directors and was on the Young Women's Christian Association board. Teed was a member of Phi Beta Kappa honorary society and the Ann Arbor Ministers Association.
She died March 28, 1954.
The collection includes correspondence, student papers, sermon outlines, newspaper clippings, and religious and inspirational writings by Mrs. Teed, Ralph W. Sockman, Seth C. and Paul S. Rees, Joseph H. Smith, and others relating to preaching, the role and activities of women in the church, the holiness movement within Methodism, and personal affairs. There is also information concerning the Women's Society of Christian Service of the Methodist Church, the American Association of Women Ministers, the Detroit Holiness Tabernacle, and the Michigan Association for the Promotion of Holiness. The photographs consist of one ambrotype and four daguerreotypes of Schleicher family children, ca. 1860-1890.
Subjects:
American Association of Women Ministers.; Ann Arbor (Mich.); Christian Witness and Advocate of Bible Holiness.; Clergy--Michigan.; Detroit Holiness Association.; Detroit Holiness Tabernacle (Mich.); First Methodist Church (Ann Arbor, Mich.); The Free Methodist.; God's revivalist and bible advocate.; Heart and life.; Methodist Church. Woman's Society of Christian Service.; Michigan Association for the Promotion of Holiness.; Women--Religious life--Michigan.; University of Michigan. Class of 1926.; The Woman's pulpit.; Women's rights--Michigan.; Teed, Florence Ernestine Schleicher, 1901-1954.; Women clergy--Michigan.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Children.; Families.; German Americans--Michigan.; Schleicher family.; Women.
Contributors:
Rees, Paul S. (Paul Stromberg); Rees, Seth Cook.; Smith, Joseph Henry, 1855-1946.; Sockman, Ralph W. (Ralph Washington), 1889-1970.
Genre Terms:
Ambrotypes.; Daguerreotypes.; Photographs.; Sermons.
- Correspondence 1919-1953
  - Correspondence 1919-1930 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence 1931-1940 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence 1941-1945 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence 1946-1950 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence 1951-1953 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence undated (Box 1)
- Sermons and other inspirational writings
  - Sermons, by Mrs. Teed (Box 1)
  - Religious and inspirational writings by Mrs. Teed (Box 1)
  - Published articles and book The Challenge of Christ 1928, by Mrs. Teed (Box 1)
  - Manuscript of book, Faith for Living, by Mrs. Teed (Box 1)
  - Non-religious writings by Mrs. Teed (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous outlines and inspirational writings (Box 1)
- Course materials
  - Tests, course outlines, and term papers 1924-1927 (Box 1)
  - Tests and term papers undated (Box 1)
- Published material
  - Sermons, articles and other material, by Paul S. Rees (Box 2)
  - Sermons, articles and other material, by Joseph H. Smith (Box 2)
  - Sermons by Ralph W. Sockman (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous sermons and religious writings (Box 2)
  - Detroit Holiness Association newsletter: The Tabernacle Tidings (Box 2)
  - Periodical articles: Christian Witness and Advocate of Bible Holiness (Box 2)
  - Periodical articles: Heart and Life (Box 2)
  - Periodical articles: The Christian Advocate (Box 2)
  - Periodical articles: Michigan Christian Advocate (Box 2)
  - Periodical articles: The Pentecostal Herald (Box 2)
  - Periodical articles: God's Revivalist, and Bible Advocate (Box 2)
  - Periodical articles: The Free Methodist (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous religious periodical articles 1900-1949 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous religious periodical articles undated (Box 2)
  - Printed miscellanea: inspirational clippings (Box 2)
  - Printed miscellanea: clippings from secular periodicals (Box 2)
  - Pamphlets (Box 2)
  - Miscellanea (Box 2)
- Photographs, circa 1860-circa 1890
  - Unidentified woman, seated, 3/4 view, daguerreotype (Box 3)
  - Three female Schleicher children: Anna Maria, Cristiana Elisabeth, and Martha, daguerreotype (Box 3)
  - Young man: Heinrich ? or Friedrich ? Schleicher, daguerreotype (Box 3)
  - Gottlob Friedrich and wife and daughter circa 1860, ambrotype (Box 3)
  - Three male Schleicher children: Louis, Carl, Friedrich, daguerreotype (Box 3)